Holger Otto André

IT Consultant & Solutions Developer at Inteligentica

hjoab1@gmail.com

Summary

I am computer scientist who loves computing science and has extensive experience in development, support, project management, sales, consulting and is constantly updating his knowledge in IT. My employers have been large corporations, small companies and individuals, national and international mainly in the USA and Europe also working remotely. I am project oriented.

More than 20 years of experience in development in many technologies and bringing consulting. I worked in development of complete projects from bottom-up (analysis, planning, design, programming, deployment and support) as well as on the improvement of applications and IT services already in production and managing teams of developers and IT experts.

I command several technologies in different degrees. I put hands to the work and research and learn what it is necessary to do it. I am fast and very effective. Because I have taken many jobs with different requirements, I was forced to learn a lot in general about IT. I have abilities for leadership and management and have dealt with customers and sales as well. In my last project I was in charge of a DevOps and QA team (using Jenkins).

I am moving toward AI development or data analysis (KDD, Data Mining, BI, Big Data, Data Science) or Machine Learning or Bots programing. I already have worked at BI & Networking Lab in HPE in Costa Rica.

Experience

IT Consultant & Solutions Developer at Inteligentica

2005 - Present

Inteligentica is my self-employed name as IT consultant and solutions developer.

Senior IT Developer

January 2018 - April 2018 (4 months)

Team Lead for the DevOps & QA Team at ReemoHealth working remotely. We learn about many tools especially Jenkins and Azure. We were the responsibles to to setup DevOps culture and tools at ReemoHealth a startup.

For a description see the attached doc below.

System Engineer 2 at Stewart Lender Services

March 2017 - October 2017 (8 months)

Systems Engineer 2 / L3 IT Support / Valuations Team

https://www.stewart.com

I was member of the Valuations team located in Costa Rica, responsible for bringing support to some of the most important applications for business operations (web and desktop applications including servers). Troubleshooting for these applications on issues in the workflow of orders and messages inbound/outbound of these applications. Incidents and Service Request from associates and external users of these applications based on tickets (between 5 and 15 daily).

P1 and P2 critical incidents (stoppages, etc) troubleshooting 24/7 for these applications: creation of bridges and chat groups adding the necessary teams to look up for a solution or workaround of the stoppage and deciding plans of action.

PRB (problem solution) tickets creation and management: RCA (Root Cause Analysis) and researching of the solution and correcting actions and recommendations involving the necessary teams to assign part of the research and the necessary CR (change requests) for the implementation of the solution.

Participation in meetings with operations and stockholders of the applications to discuss the last most important issues of the week affecting those systems (stoppages, general problems and solutions, etc.)

Participation in meetings with PRB tickets reviewing board to discuss advances of the research and correcting actions.

Manage of projects for the creation of solutions for automation and transition to L2 of tasks and tickets processing.

Creation of SLQ scripts, stored procedures and another programmed code for automation of different tasks and queries of services requests.

Documentation of all the necessary processes and solutions and any other necessary information related to the duties and work.

I entered as System Engineer 1 and was promoted to Systems Engineer 2 in 3 months. I was the best employee of the month for May.

Web Software Engineer at Hewlett Packard Enterprise

May 2015 - May 2016 (1 year 1 month)

Outsourcing from OTSI (https://www.facebook.com/OTSICostaRica/)

HPE Manager: Esteban Corella <ecorella@hpe.com>

OTSI Manager: Fabian Montealegre <fmontealegre@otsi-usa.com>

I was part of the BI & Networking Lab in HPE in Costa Rica. As such I worked in 4 different projects of the most relevant importance for the high top executives at HP. I used technologies like VSTO

for Excel programming form c#, nested AJAX using JQuery and JSON in ASP.NET MVC, SQL Server using especial methods. I write the documentation of all them.

See under projects

Web Software Engineer & PM February 2014 - March 2015 (1 year 2 months)

http://www.myemarketplaces.com/

(Telecommuting)

Owner: Lee Hinman <info@myemarketplaces.info>

I converted (partially) the legacy web site for a PSC (Parametric Shopping Cart) into the new version on DNN 7.3 (dotnetnuke) and NB_Store module. The PSC is a patented solution for a DCSE (Dynamic Comparison Shopping Engine).

This web app was developed as 2 pieces app.

- 1) The vendors/merchants part was the vendors own web site based on PSC that connects to
- 2) A bigger market place part where vendors connects to offer their products.

Whenever a user searched on a market place (2) for a product, he is asked some question (parameters) to refine the search. Later a RFQ was issue to the vendors' sites (1) who offers the product with all the options matched. Then the info is displayed to the buyer to be added to the shopping card.

I made the documentation and brought support and troubleshooting on the servers and IIS installation and others.

I did consulting on different subjects as what technologies to use and how to implement them and on ideas about the final solution and on how to merchandise it.

Software Engineer at Optria LLC May 2013 - January 2014 (9 months)

http://www.optria.com/ (Telecommuting)

I worked in a development team from USA, Belarus, Russia and Costa Rica using Internet communication tools. Optria is a cyber-company specialized in the generation of customized printed and html (web) bank statements, notices and reports for banks customers in USA. Optria process the ugly printed statements generated by legacy or actual software of the banks and transforms them into more look appealing and customized statements to be printed by the bank and sent by mail as PDFs or display in as web pages at banks web sites (thru iStatements). For this, a proprietary tool named Communiqué is used as well as c# (as dlls libraries) and JavaScript

code that are bound to the Communiqué server to solve some programming issues and create some special effects. I was assigned many Communiqué development projects and some web development task (iStatements).

Web Software Engineer at Intel Corporation (Costa Rica) September 2012 - April 2013 (8 months)

http://exploreintel.com/costarica

Outsourcing from Grupo Babel (http://www.grupobabel.com/)

I was part of the Predator Team (of 5) managed by Dave Evans (from INTEL at Folsom). Some very aggressive and high intensive programming web applications projects (SCRUM, RTC, C#, ASP .Net Ajax (controls), XML, JS, JQuery, SQL Server, IIS, Tortoise/SharpSVN, CKEditor, etc.). We were updating a legacy tool the BSpec INTEL web site among others things. BSpec is a kind a wiki site used internally to show and edit technical documents about chip designs in formats like html, bxml and images. The docs were SVN-ated (using sharpSVN) and changes made by the authors must be committed to the repository. It has many features like emailing for the approvals and rejections of the changes by editors on-line and off-line.

Web Software Engineer January 2012 - August 2012 (8 months)

http://www.perhead.com/

I was part of a team of 3 developers that give support to the agents' site (http://www.beteagleagents.ag/). It was an ASP.NET website based in XML to request info from SQL Server than later was used to generate HTML using XSLT functionality in c# and JavaScript, etc. The site was original developed by DGS but Perhead broke the relationship. There were 2 kernel .dll (in C#) with no source code and so many important SPs encrypted in the SQLServer. So we got .Net Reflector and SQL DeCryptor to do the job. Before that, all the programmers had to make a shortcut programming around, guessing how to make the calls to the kernel and SPs. After that, Perhead was able to re-engineering the web site.

Channel Partner at NLogix Solutions

November 2010 - November 2011 (1 year 1 month)

http://www.nlogixsolutions.com

Since 2010, Inteligentica (aka HABCO) was a channel partner of bigger IT companies from India like

Nlogix Solutions and Agogue Group.

As that, I was responsible of acquiring new clients for HABCO and their channel partners, to lead the negotiations till complete the sales.

Lead Programmer & PM at GPN DATA GROUP INTERNATIONAL

August 2010 - August 2011 (1 year 1 month)

http://www.gpndata.com/

(At office at the beginning and Telecommuting later)

Programming and support to an online payment system (gateway) (http://www.glopronet.com/) (Windows Server/PHP/SQL-Server) for credit cards and others electronic payments processing based on REST for GPN Data cyber-company from Poland / Costa Rica / Croatia. I developed a REST (based in an XML) API tester and a backend application for this old system in VB.net. Later I started the new system GPN Pay 2.0 design to be in Visual Studio 2010 (ASP.NET), SQL Server 2008.

Software Engineer & PM (TourMaster)

January 2008 - August 2010 (2 years 8 months)

http://www.aratours.com/

I designed and developed the big Tourmaster, a desktop tour operator software to fulfill the database needs about production activities, including eBusiness / eCommerce, contracts generation for suppliers (hotels, etc.) and catalogues generation for clients and automatic feeding to Tourplan. I made the business analysis, design and was the lead programmer. The development was in Visual Studio 2008 (VB, C#), SQL Server 2008 and Office 2007. After months of continue delays, ARA Tours decided not to continue with the development. The project was ready in around 85%.

English Teacher

April 2006 - October 2007 (1 year 7 months)

Basic Levels English Teacher at the private English language learning institute INISYS.

English & Mathematics Teacher

June 2005 - March 2006 (10 months)

Basic Mathematics and English teacher for high school level students at the private institute NISSI.

Software Engineer & PM (CARsys) at Novartis and Gerber

March 2004 - February 2005 (1 year)

http://www.novartis.com/

Outsourcing from Engine Solutions.

I developed the big CARsys (System for Control of Assets and Resources) to control projects (like factories construction) budget, planning and execution and for the expenditures and resources assigned. I was hired by Engine Solutions responsible of the development. With 8 modules and 36 tables in total, a multi-company and multi-budget was developed in VB.Net, Access and SQL Server. I made the analysis, design and was the only programmer. I became the manager of the project. It can be classified as an extreme RAD. I left the project (80% completed) because health concerns.

Education

Universidad de Costa Rica Licentiate degree, Computer and Information Sciences, 2003 - 2005 Universidad Estatal a Distancia Licentiate degree, Computer and Information Sciences, 2013 - 2017 Universidad de Costa Rica Bachelor's degree, Computer and Information Sciences, 1999 - 2005

Holger Otto André

IT Consultant & Solutions Developer at Inteligentica

hjoab1@gmail.com



Contact Holger Otto on LinkedIn